<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home of Sara on Traveling Engineer</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home of Sara on Traveling Engineer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://travelingengineer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aviermore, Scotland</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-19-aviermore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-19-aviermore/</guid><description>We had a couple free weeks in between our time in Edinburgh for the visa interview and Dan&amp;rsquo;s work. Knowing we&amp;rsquo;d be back to Edinburgh for 3+ weeks later, we wanted to explore some other parts of Scotland, but not travel a ton. We decided to pick 2 places, each for a week. Our criteria was nature, accessible by train, walkable to a town, yard for kids and relaxing house. We went to the map view of AirBnb and started looking.</description></item><item><title>Edinburgh, Scotland</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-16-edinburgh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-16-edinburgh/</guid><description>We arrived into Edinburgh and after being on a train for 3.5 hours, a walk to our Airbnb sounded better than a taxi. Google said 15 minutes, but it forgot to account for the giant staircases! Dan had to take 2 trips.
Once we cleared the numerous sets of stairs, we had a very easy walk, passing by cool thing after cool thing.
Within minutes of getting inside our AirBnb, I was doing laundry.</description></item><item><title>Castleton, England</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-13-castleton/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-13-castleton/</guid><description>In the Peak District National Park, there are tons of YHAs, think in the teens maybe? A lot are closed for the season or only open if you rent the WHOLE place, but the one outside Castleton was the one that caught Dan&amp;rsquo;s eye the most. It was booked most nights so we were only able to get it for 2 nights. In hindsight, we should have just skipped it and stayed at the Hartington one 2 more nights and avoided a pack up/unpack day, but you know what they say about hindsight.</description></item><item><title>Hartington, England</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-10-hartington/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-10-hartington/</guid><description>This part of our trip had really turned into &amp;lsquo;make plans for next place, while you are in the current place&amp;rsquo;. We knew Dan had to be in Sheffield for a talk on the 15th, but we were waiting to hear for our interview date and location, so didn&amp;rsquo;t want to plan too far in advanced. We had the car booked until the 19th in Aberdeen, where we were planning to catch a ferry to Shetland.</description></item><item><title>Snowdonia National Park, Wales</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-06-snowdonia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-06-snowdonia/</guid><description>On our way to Snowdonia, we stopped in Portmadog for groceries and dinner items at a bakery. The hostel was in a pretty remote area and we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to drive if we could avoid it. We were going to be there for 4 nights, so we got food for 3 dinners, 4 lunches and 3 breakfasts, knowing we&amp;rsquo;d eat there a bit. No surprise, but we got too much.</description></item><item><title>Talsarnau, Wales</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-02-talsarnau/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2024-01-02-talsarnau/</guid><description>Wales was never on the list, but having an extra month in the UK (since we didn&amp;rsquo;t go to Egypt for the month of January) we had time to explore. No big plan of where, so we looked at a map of the UK and gravitated to the National Parks and hiking areas. The general plan for the UK was Airbnb for a few nights (for space and laundry) and then a few nights in a hostel, for social-ness, extra books, games and food served to you when it had just been a long day.</description></item><item><title>Bath</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-30-bath/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-30-bath/</guid><description>When planning where to stay/what to do in the UK before heading to Edinburgh, Dan mentioned staying in youth hostels. Note: This was the day before when we were in London and didn&amp;rsquo;t have a place to stay the next night yet. I have stayed at my fair share of hostels and know they have their ranges, but it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t on my radar for this trip for some reason. He brought up the YHA UK website and just starts flashing cool place after cool place we could stay.</description></item><item><title>Travel Day to London + 1 Night in London</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-29-travel-day-london/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-29-travel-day-london/</guid><description>No actual stress, which is VERY surprising considering the number of transfers and shear amount of travel time, but we did have my super power of traveling karma on our side.
We knew we had to give ourselves extra time for our train from Brussels to London, so with nothing planned that morning, we had a breakfast in, wrapped up packing and grabbed the tram to the Ghent train station. Uber never responded and really the tram was so easy before.</description></item><item><title>Ghent</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-26-ghent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-26-ghent/</guid><description>The location of our Airbnb was amazing. 1 block to the castle, 2 blocks to the Christmas market while walking over a bridge and by so many cafes, restaurants and shops.
As before, didn&amp;rsquo;t stay long, just dropped our stuff and headed out. We needed food and just the little we saw walking from the wrong tram stop, we were already loving it. And Dan had met a family the day before at the part and they said we&amp;rsquo;d love Ghent.</description></item><item><title>Bruges</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-23-bruges/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-23-bruges/</guid><description>Out of the train station and we found a van taxi. 15 minutes later we were at our Airbnb. I had picked a place outside of town, as the ones in town that fit 6 were $600+ a night. This place was 1.5km from town and we figured we could walk or take numerous taxis a day and still come out ahead. This may have been one of my best picks!</description></item><item><title>Brussels</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-20-brussels/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-20-brussels/</guid><description>It was a glorious reunion with lots of hugs, even with an exhausted grandma and dad.
We thought they were going to get in after us, but turns out they both landed into Frankfurt early and I mentioned, ‘why don’t you check if your tickets allow for riding on the earlier train so you don’t have to wait around 2 extra hours.’ Well, they wouldn’t have, but their train was canceled, so now they can!</description></item><item><title>Liege, Belgium</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-17-liege/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-17-liege/</guid><description>Our second night in Paris I was on Facebook and saw a photo of Elena (Ben’s nanny from when he was an infant and we lived in Boston) and her husband, Robert, on an airplane. I assumed Oaxaca, but her husband is Belgian, so just threw it out there and asked where they were going as we were going to be in Belgium. They were flying to Belgium! Within hours, we had a trip planned for us to meet up with them!</description></item><item><title>Paris, Part 2</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-15-paris-part2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-15-paris-part2/</guid><description>Not huge plans today, but did want to make it to the Sacre-Coeur. We hopped the subway and these cars had doors that you could open yourself, EVEN before the train was fully stopped! Kids loved it so much!
At one point, Ben and Sam stood at different doors and opened them for everyone. The Metro dumped us out a few blocks from the base and we had to walk through shops and shops of souvenir stores, where the kids wanted to stop every 3 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Paris, Part 1</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-12-paris-part1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-12-12-paris-part1/</guid><description>There is so much to say about Paris, that I won’t dwell much on the trip there…nor how hard the goodbyes were or how much we will miss Turkey. Direct flight, too much turbulence but we made it. Quick taxi to the AirBnb, with the most elaborate check-in process…codes, 5 doors, ugh.
We basically dumped our bags into the smallest apartment (someone with serious skills took photos for the listing to make it look small/normal size) and walked to a supermarket for food for dinner.</description></item><item><title>Naples &amp; Pompeii</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-23-naples-pompeii/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-23-naples-pompeii/</guid><description>I had heard mixed feelings about Naples, but I wasn’t too concerned as we were so excited about seeing Pompeii, nothing could deter us. Yes, it felt a bit rough around the edges, but we liked it. Felt a lot like Genoa, another Italian port city.
Our Airbnb host let us check in at noon because no one had been there the night before. Quickly did the walk through and headed to a pizza place for lunch she recommended.</description></item><item><title>Rome</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-21-rome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-21-rome/</guid><description>So pleasantly surprised with Rome! I had been once before&amp;hellip;I was 23yo, it was a very hot July and so crowded. I felt very unwanted by locals and without the internet to guide me, I kept picking terrible restaurants that seemed to always be trying to charge me for something I didn&amp;rsquo;t order. I had no desire to go back! But when our friends told us they were going to be there and asked if we wanted to meet, I figured I could suffer through it.</description></item><item><title>Belgrade, Part 2</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-19-belgrade-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-19-belgrade-part2/</guid><description>Today was the day I had organized a walking tour with a private guide (through AirBnB experiences). It didn’t start until 11am, but I wanted to get early breakfast AND a late breakfast in, with a lot of chill time as to not losing energy beforehand. We have a bakery right across the street, and once all the kids were up (Ben slept in until 8:30am!), I ran across to get Serbian croissants and some other baked goods.</description></item><item><title>Belgrade, Part 1</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-17-belgrade-part1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-17-belgrade-part1/</guid><description>Due to our lack of extended visas, the kids and I were going to extend our ‘leave Turkey by date’ with a few days added onto our 5 day planned Italy trip. So why did I pick Belgrade? Well, it started with a search of direct flights from Ankara, that were outside Turkey and were geographically located between Turkey and Rome (where we were headed to next). Then I narrowed it down to places I hadn’t been before and that had direct flights to Rome.</description></item><item><title>Capadoyka</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-03-capadoyka/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-11-03-capadoyka/</guid><description>Easy, uneventful drive for 2.5hrs of the 3hrs. Once we made our last main turn, the landscape changed to something I can’t even explain. There were rock ‘chimneys’ that looked like giant gnome hats, a distant mesa that had some Grand Canyon feeling, more weird shaped rocks and layer after layer rock that had eroded away.
We pulled into Gorome, where we’d be staying for 3 nights and we were all kinda giddy school children.</description></item><item><title>Istanbul</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-10-27-istanbul/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-10-27-istanbul/</guid><description>There is so much to say about Istanbul, but overwhelming in every sense of the word is what comes to mind. Overall, it was totally an exhausting weekend and we were so done with the crowds, people pestering you to look in their shop, lack of places to walk safely (sidewalks were a joke) and worrying about losing a kid or having them hit by a car. The city seemed to go on forever and we didn’t even see that much!</description></item><item><title>Mengen</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-10-20-mengen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-10-20-mengen/</guid><description>We needed mountains and nature in a desperate way, but not a really long drive. We found an area by Mengen that had a bunch of cool places to stay and it was about an hour from a national park we wanted to check out. Our friends, Kelly, Ramsey and their 3 boys, wanted to join and as the search got underway, Kelly found a place where we could stay in hobbit houses.</description></item><item><title>A Day in Ankara</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-10-01-ankara/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-10-01-ankara/</guid><description>We were feeling the need for some exploring and to drench ourselves in some Turkish culture. The weather forecast was for rain, so we picked the Museum of Anatolian Civilizations to visit. Our trusty Lonely Planet book raved about it, so we thought we’d give it a go. We headed out of our place and with just a sprinkling of rain, we walked briskly over to a taxi stand and had no problem finding one at about 9:15am.</description></item><item><title>More Turkey</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-16-more-turkey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-16-more-turkey/</guid><description>We lasted a total of 10 days before we needed to get out exploring a bit. Not having figured out the buses or subway yet, we caught a cab to the center of Ankara. Also being only $9USD, we might take a while to figure it out. :) If felt good being in the heart of the city and taking in all the sights, smells, etc. It took a bit to find the castle entrance from where we were dropped off, but we finally figured out we needed to just walk straight up the huge flight of stairs.</description></item><item><title>First bit in Ankara</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-15-first-bit-in-ankara/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-15-first-bit-in-ankara/</guid><description>Waking up in our 4-month temporary home was a grand feeling. We ate yogurt, museli and fruit and the kids and I lounged as we thought about what we were going to do for the day. Dan had to get papers in for his class that were due that day and had to be reviewed by the dean, so he was up and out in the morning to return the car (the only time he drove in the last 2 months!</description></item><item><title>Travel Day to Turkey</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-05-travel-day-ankara/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-05-travel-day-ankara/</guid><description>When starting to plan this trip, I had the romantic idea of getting from Nice, France to Ankara, Turkey without stepping foot on an airplane. A combination of buses, ferries, trains and rental cars would be much more fun and adventurous, right? To be 100% honest, I don’t regret any of it…except maybe the final push from Sofia, Bulgaria? (Just kidding, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t change a second of any of it!) But we had come this far, we couldn’t quit now.</description></item><item><title>Bachkovo Monestary &amp; Final Night in Sofia</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-04-drive-sofia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-04-drive-sofia/</guid><description>There were 2 monasteries that Ben had mentioned, but with a drive ahead of us and big travel days the next day for all of us, we picked just one&amp;hellip;the one that required less out of the way driving. The drive in was beautiful and we were fully immersed in the trees. It was raining and not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s usually crowded (there was a big parking lot), but it was pretty empty for us.</description></item><item><title>Plovdiv</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-01-plovdiv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-09-01-plovdiv/</guid><description>I had gotten into the habit of writing about our travels every few nights. This doesn’t work so when you travel with friends and you stay up chatting each night. In Bulgaria I got a bit behind on my writing and to be totally honest, am writing this about 4 weeks after we left Plovdiv. It really was a special place for me (all of us actually) and knew I had so much to say, maybe for that I have felt the task a bit daunting.</description></item><item><title>Byala, The Black Sea</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-29-byala/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-29-byala/</guid><description>It’s dinner time after a long day, but you have just arrived to the Black Sea. How do you not go check it out? Laura, the kids and I went (way) down to the beach just to “check it out for a few minutes” and Dan and Ben headed out to get dinner. Best laid plans always stay the course, right? The water was so pleasant, soft sand and bigger than expected waves.</description></item><item><title>Veliko Tarnovo</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-28-veliko-tarnovo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-28-veliko-tarnovo/</guid><description>The next morning, we were treated to more pastry items that the dads went out to get. A breakfast of trying to use up some food and Big Ben, Sam and I headed to the airport to pick up our rental cars. Sam and Ben were playing the ‘drums’ to the beat of the music on the way there and Sam was in love. He was so cuddly with Ben the whole ride and while we were getting the cars.</description></item><item><title>Sofia</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-25-sofia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-25-sofia/</guid><description>We settled into our Airbnb and decided to run a couple errands before our friends were arriving the next day at 10am. Ben needed shoes so badly…his trusty Keens were holding up well, but were also a bit smelly. If by a bit, I mean very! We had washed them a few times, but didn’t seem to do the trick for long. We headed out towards my favorite kids’ store, Okaidi, which was located on a pedestrian walkway.</description></item><item><title>Skopje</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-21-skopje/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-21-skopje/</guid><description>We really didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect with Skopje. I really don&amp;rsquo;t think I knew of it until I started planning this trip, and even then I didn&amp;rsquo;t put much thought into it. We ended up really enjoying it.
Easy check-in to the Airbnb and it was awesome! It was the 3rd floor, so a bit hot since the AC hadn’t had time to cool it down, but as soon as we walked in, the kids went crazy!</description></item><item><title>Ohrid</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-16-ohrid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-16-ohrid/</guid><description>Arriving into the bus station, we easily grabbed a taxi. We didn’t have Macedonian denar yet, but they would take euros (bills only, or paper as the guy stated). We were out of paper euros, but Ben had some. Once again, we had to raid Ben’s euro savings for cash.
We got dropped off at the upper gate and followed picture directions (photos with arrows on them) from our Airbnb host.</description></item><item><title>Tirana</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-14-tirana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-14-tirana/</guid><description>Another long goodbye as the kids had taken quite a liking to the bed and breakfast owners and visa versa.
We got help carrying out suitcases us the stairs to the car and we were off. Easy 3hr drive to Tirana, I dropped everyone off at the Airbnb and drove to the hotel to drop off the car. Due to a suggestion from the guy at the rental place, I took the bus back to the city center and then walked to our place.</description></item><item><title>Gjirokaster</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-11-gjirokaster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-11-gjirokaster/</guid><description>Our place was amazing! Right in the heart of it all, in an old renovated building with a large terrace out back and the sweetest couple that owned/ran it.
We needed food and the owner had recommended a place, Taverna Murgana. We walked about 4 minutes, through the bazaar to above the mosque. The place was just what we needed. A back patio with no other patrons outside…we were still pretty early.</description></item><item><title>Harry Potter and Apollonia</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-10-harry-potter-and-apollinia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-10-harry-potter-and-apollinia/</guid><description>After our long goodbyes, we started out drive to Gjirokaster. We were in a critical part of Harry Potter, The Goblet of Fire and the kids and I were completely engrossed, begging Dan to keep reading. I never read the Harry Potter books, but always planned to when/if I had kids. I want to state I was NEVER against the books, but 7 books in a set would have taken a lot of time and when I start a series, I can’t stop!</description></item><item><title>Berat, Albania</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-08-berat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-08-berat/</guid><description>A UNESCO World Heritage site and nick named ‘The Town of a Thousand Windows’. Seeing photos and knowing it’s significance, this was clearly going to be a stop on our trip. I had planned to spend a few nights there, but looking back, I think we did it right with a day trip from magical Alpeta Winery. An easy 30 minute drive down the mountain and we were there. Found street parking (that we hoped was, and was, allowed) and started walking to the center.</description></item><item><title>Alpeta Winery, Albania</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-06-albania-alpeta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-06-albania-alpeta/</guid><description>I want to start this post with talking about how I have never (and I mean never and I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled a LOT) felt so welcomed into a country as I/we have in Albania. Within minutes my kids are on hugging terms with waiters and people from where we stayed. Older people would walk up to us in the streets, bend down to the kids level and start speaking to the kids (in Albanian) with huge smiles on their faces.</description></item><item><title>Lipa Cave and Podgorica</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-05-lipa-cave-and-podgorica-copy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-08-05-lipa-cave-and-podgorica-copy/</guid><description>We had to return the rental car by noon to Podgorica, but really wanted to stop at Lipa Cave on the way as other days in Lovcen National Park, we just didn’t want to leave. The first tour of the day was 10am and lasted an hour. Drive to our Podgorica hotel was 45minutes and another 20 to the airport…what could go wrong? Oh and we needed gas.
I really didn’t want to have the 10am tour fill up, so I wanted to leave by 8:30 to get there by 9:15 to be safe.</description></item><item><title>Montenegro</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-31-montenegro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-31-montenegro/</guid><description>The drive from Trebinje, Bosnia and Herzegonia to Centije, Montenegro was supposed to be a little over 2 hours. Supposed to be…we were all optimistic with the border crossing into Bosnia and Herzegovina being 5 minutes, but not so much heading into Montenegro. At the border, times were getting dire. Kids were hungry, but we didn’t want to bust out all the food in the car and usually Harry Potter reading will suffice, but nothing worked…and 4 of us had to go to the bathroom.</description></item><item><title>Trebinje</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-27-trebinje/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-27-trebinje/</guid><description>After our late lunch in Pocitelj, the kids pretty much went right to bed once we checked into our apartment.
I made a quick run to the grocery store in the morning so we could do breakfast in, some school work and then head out to explore a bit. We were 2 blocks from the river and had lots of tree lined streets to walk down. We crossed a bridge and headed into the old town.</description></item><item><title>Pocitelj</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-26-pocitelj/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-26-pocitelj/</guid><description>Max and I took the bus to the airport to get the rental car and then swung back to get the rest of them. I just couldn’t handle us all loading stuff on a bus and getting all sweaty so early…and it worked out for Dan to get some school time in with the 2 older kids.
As we are starting the drive and just getting out of town, Dan asks if I want the scenic route or the highway.</description></item><item><title>Split</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-22-split/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-22-split/</guid><description>The age-old story when backpacking through Europe…you land at 7am, but can’t check in until 3pm. Our Airbnb host said we could at least drop our stuff off at 11am. With heat, 3 kids and luggage, 4 hours seemed like eternity. We started off by finding a restaurant, piling our stuff up and getting some food. 45 minutes down. It was hot, so we thought a museum would be a good idea.</description></item><item><title>San Marino</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-20-san-marino/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-20-san-marino/</guid><description>All the holding up of the Pisa Tower tuckered these kids out. :)
And it seems the car was concerned about my tiredness because it let me know I had been driving for an hour and needed a coffee. Only in Italy!
As we turned off the autostrada (fast tollway) and followed our trusty google maps, we could see a tower and a castle way off in the distance on top a giant hill.</description></item><item><title>Pisa</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-19-pisa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-19-pisa/</guid><description>For months Sam has been talking about seeing the Leaning Tower of Pisa. I have seen it and it wasn’t high on my list to see again, but the excitement he had about seeing it made me want to fit it in. I don’t think we would have gone too far out of our way to see it, but it was only a 20 min train ride from where our ferry docked and we knew it would be late by the time we got there…meaning we wouldn’t want to continue on to San Marino that day.</description></item><item><title>Corsica</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-14-corsica/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-14-corsica/</guid><description>Getting to Corsica from Genoa was a trek! We had a 7:45am train to catch, so at 7am we were walking to an area we had seen taxis the day before. (No cars were allowed where our Airbnb was, so we had to get past the square area. No taxis. We started walking in the direction of the train station and for 20 minutes a taxi never passed us. Oh well.</description></item><item><title>Genoa</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-12-genoa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-12-genoa/</guid><description>This time I swore after a big day we were going to have a chill one. Morning at a pirate ship, lunch at home and maybe some afternoon wandering around. It did not go as planned.
After breakfast at home of yogurt and bananas we were off to the pirate ship. On the way we checked out the deterioration of some columns and saw talked about the order of how part of it was patched.</description></item><item><title>Cinque Terra</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-11-cinque-terra/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-11-cinque-terra/</guid><description>When your good friend from high school is in Florence and you are in Genoa at the same time, how do you not meet in the middle in Cinque Terra? We planned to take the direct 9:54am train but when we got there to buy tickets, it was sold out! We would have had to wait an hour and had a transfer. If we weren’t meeting up with Rona and family, we would have just postponed for another day.</description></item><item><title>Travel Day to Genoa</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-10-travel-to-genoa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-10-travel-to-genoa/</guid><description>By 8am, when I was up starting to pack, it was hot (sense a theme here) and I was already sweating. I tried to move slow, but anytime I was in the sun, it was hard not to. We planned to walk the 400m to the bus stop with our stuff when our Airbnb host seems to think that was a bit much and offered to drive the stuff. Dan went with the stuff and the kids and I walked down.</description></item><item><title>Monaco</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-09-monaco/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-09-monaco/</guid><description>This was a bit of a forced day. We had a big walking day the day before (around Nice) and were 2 days post trans-Atlantic flight, but it was really our only day to go to Monaco…and I was so curios to see it. We took a hot and crowded bus there and went straight to the central market for food. Kids found a playground and Dan and I were able to sit and drink a coffee in the plaza and be close enough to see the kids.</description></item><item><title>Nice</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-07-nice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-07-nice/</guid><description>True to myself, I woke up in a new city and I was ready to go explore! I have traveled with kids a lot and have created the rule of thumb…whatever you have planned, divide by 2. The ‘plan’ was to hike up to a fort with some views, walk to our cousins&amp;rsquo; (Mark and Shayna) place, tram to their new place, swing by the market for street food, go to a water fountain, stroll the streets of old town and maybe a quick dip in the sea before dinner.</description></item><item><title>The 'Plan'</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-05-the-plan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-05-the-plan/</guid><description>The “Plan” I put this in quotation marks as it has already changed numerous times from when the seed got planted back in September 2022 and it will continue to change. But I will update it regularly so you can know where we at least think we might be in the future and where we have been.
July 2023: Nice, France – Monaco – Genoa, Italy – Calvi, Corsica (France) – San Marino – Split, Croatia – Trebinje, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina August 2023: Podgorica, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovia – Berat, Albania – Gjkloster, Albania – Tirana, Albania, Ohrid, North Macedonia – Skopje, North Macedonia – Sofia, Bulgaria – Byala, Bulgaria September 2023: Plovdiv, Bulgaria – (Back to) Sofia, Bulgaria – Istanbul, Turkey – Ankara, Turkey October 2023: Ankara, Turkey November 2023: Ankara, Turkey December 2023: Ankara, Turkey – Jordan January 2024: Cairo, Egypt – Luxor, Egypt February 2024: Morocco?</description></item><item><title>To Europe and Beyond!!!</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-06-travel-to-europe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-06-travel-to-europe/</guid><description>We visited family before our jaunt across the pond. This meant we had an 8hr flight to Frankfurt, not a longer one from the West Coast. Pro: Less time on airplane. Con: Kids sleep great, but with dinner, there was no way to get anything more than 5hrs of sleep for them…1 for me.
With a big of a delayed flight and customs, we didn’t have much time. Bathroom yes, coffee for Dan no.</description></item><item><title>Packing</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-01-packing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-01-packing/</guid><description>I consider myself a humble person when it comes to most things, but packing…I will brag about my skills all day long. 2 week trip to Europe for myself and 3 kids in 2 carry-ons? With cold weather clothes and marathon outfit? No problem. Backpacking trip for the 5 of us to all fit in Dan’s backpack? With snow gear? In my sleep. But packing for a year for the family and still being able to move about…I struggled with this.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://travelingengineer.com/page/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://travelingengineer.com/page/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll do this eventually :)</description></item></channel></rss>