<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Traveling Engineer</title>
    <link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Traveling Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://travelingengineer.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monaco</title>
      <link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-09-monaco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-09-monaco/</guid>
      <description>This was a bit of a forced day. We had a big walking day the day before (around Nice) and were 2 days post trans-Atlantic flight, but it was really our only day to go to Monaco…and I was so curios to see it. We took a hot and crowded bus there and went straight to the central market for food. Kids found a playground and Dan and I were able to sit and drink a coffee in the plaza and be close enough to see the kids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice</title>
      <link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-07-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-07-nice/</guid>
      <description>True to myself, I woke up in a new city and I was ready to go explore! I have traveled with kids a lot and have created the rule of thumb…whatever you have planned, divide by 2. The ‘plan’ was to hike up to a fort with some views, walk to our cousin’s (Mark and Shayna) place, tram to their new place, swing by the market for street food, go to a water fountain, stroll the streets of old town and maybe a quick dip in the sea before dinner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Plan&#39;</title>
      <link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-05-the-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-05-the-plan/</guid>
      <description>The “Plan” I put this in quotation marks as it has already changed numerous times from when the seed got planted back in September 2022 and it will continue to change. But I will update it regularly so you can know where we at least think we might be in the future and where we have been.
July 2023: Nice, France – Monaco – Genoa, Italy – Calvi, Corsica (France) – San Marino – Split, Croatia – Trebinje, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina August 2023: Podgorica, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovia – Berat, Albania – Gjkloster, Albania – Tirana, Albania, Ohrid, North Macedonia – Skopje, North Macedonia – Sofia, Bulgaria – Byala, Bulgaria September 2023: Plovdiv, Bulgaria – (Back to) Sofia, Bulgaria – Istanbul, Turkey – Ankara, Turkey October 2023: Ankara, Turkey November 2023: Ankara, Turkey December 2023: Ankara, Turkey – Jordan January 2024: Cairo, Egypt – Luxor, Egypt February 2024: Morocco?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Europe and Beyond!!!</title>
      <link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-06-travel-to-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-06-travel-to-europe/</guid>
      <description>We visited family before our jaunt across the pond. This meant we had an 8hr flight to Frankfurt, not a longer one from the West Coast. Pro: Less time on airplane. Con: Kids sleep great, but with dinner, there was no way to get anything more than 5hrs of sleep for them…1 for me.
With a big of a delayed flight and customs, we didn’t have much time. Bathroom yes, coffee for Dan no.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packing</title>
      <link>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-01-packing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travelingengineer.com/blog/2023-07-01-packing/</guid>
      <description>I consider myself a humble person when it comes to most things, but packing…I will brag about my skills all day long. 2 week trip to Europe for myself and 3 kids in 2 carry-ons? With cold weather clothes and marathon outfit? No problem. Backpacking trip for the 5 of us to all fit in Dan’s backpack? With snow gear? In my sleep. But packing for a year for the family and still being able to move about…I struggled with this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
